Rohan Chambers

Social Media Technologist at We Are Social

rohanchambers888@yahoo.com

Summary

I have 4 years experience of front-end development for commercial clients on both client and agency side. I have good management skills, attention to detail in my work and I am good communicator.

I am currently working as a front end developer mainly using HTML5, CSS3 and jQuery while being exposed to some dynamic coding such as PHP, JavaScript and Wordpress template integration along with some MVC framework exposure. I work to W3C standards with a good awareness of usability and accessibility best practices. All the code I develop is cross browser compatible and SEO friendly.

In the past I have had exposure to 3D modelling and animation, video editing and DVD authoring.

Specialties

- Semantic XHTML, HTML5, CSS3, iQuery development
- Responsive design implementation
- Good knowledge of SEO and accessibility best practices
- Coding to W3C standards
- Email newsletter dev.
- Facebook App. dev.
- Cross browser compatibility
- Coda IDE, Adobe CS, SVN, MAMP, FTP

Experience

Social Media Technologist at We Are Social

October 2012 - Present (2 months)

We Are Social is a conversation agency with offices in New York, London, Paris, Milan, Munich, Singapore, Sydney & São Paulo. We help brands to listen, understand and engage in conversations in social media.

We're already helping adidas, Heinz, Unilever, Heineken, eBay, Jaguar, Intel, Moët & Chandon & Expedia.

Front End Developer at Collective London

November 2010 - October 2012 (2 years)

Working on brands such as:

- London 2012 Olympics
- EA Games
- Honda UK
- BBC
- Callaway

- Sheba
- London 2012 Olympics

I have recently finished working on the London 2012 Support your Team and Pulse sites. I developed the complete front end builds and responsive design implementations along with 75% of the JavaScript/jQuery development.

View my case studies below which have live url's:

http://www.rohanchambers.net/case-study/london2012/supportyourteam

http://www.rohanchambers.net/case-study/london2012/pulse

http://www.rohanchambers.net/case-study/london2012/dashboard

• EA - Harry Potter DH2

I fully developed the front end build to the latest Harry Potter game support site along with the Facebook tab page.

- 55K hits a month on the main site
- -500K + fans

http://harrypotter.ea.com/

• Sheba - Follow your Passion Front end build of the holding page http://uk.sheba.com/

• Honda UK

I fully developed the front end build for the Honda hub sites such as:

Honda Dream factory

http://hub.honda.co.uk/dreamfactory/

Honda stories

http://hub.honda.co.uk/

4 recommendations available upon request

Freelance, Front-end Developer at Wunderman

2010 - 2010 (less than a year)

- Front-end development of modules for a Facebook page build for the Land Rover and Range Rover car brands. I developed these modules in XHTML and CSS with strict accessibility and W3C web standards. Html Newsletter template builds for Ford and Nokia. All work passed through a QA team for passing Wunderman's high standard of delivery.
- Front end developer working on the Pringles 'Help the Oversharers' brand campaign. Mainly XHTML and CSS build's of new pages with strict accessibility and W3C standards. Also working on the Ford brand doing

XML amends and encoding flash video.

Freelance, Front-end Developer at Elvis

2010 - 2010 (less than a year)

• Front end developer working on Premier Foods brand websites such as Cadbury, Bird's, Mr. Kipling and many more. Mainly XHTML and CSS builds.

Freelance, Front-end Developer at Conran Design Group

2010 - 2010 (less than a year)

• Front-end development for a KPMG Burberry website. I was working on the build of the site with another front-end developer. This site is heavily based on the jQuery library and plugins for its functionality. Very tight deadline of 4 days to develop. Internal site only for KPMG Employees.

Freelance, Web Designer/Developer at Qube Networks

2009 - 2009 (less than a year)

Fully re-designed and developed the Qube Networks site to give a more professional look and feel to the brand.

1 recommendation available upon request

Web Developer at Playboy Enterprises, Inc.

October 2006 - October 2009 (3 years 1 month)

- Front end development of modules for the launch of Playboy.co.uk 2009.
- Working along side an external agency that were creating the
- back-end development and the integration of a taylored CMS. (VYRE)
- The main day to day tasks are keeping Playboy.co.uk up to date with new content such as builds of new pages, for ad campaigns, new deals and packages. Expanding sections for all Playboy affiliated sites.
- Working on email development that we sent out to all our Playboy subscribers after being trained on and using Email Reaction.
- I re-developed the Playboy TV France and New Zealand micro-sites.
- Fully developed the new Playboy Corporate site (pbtv.eu/), the Playboy UK Blog using wordpress but at the same time incorporating the Playboy look & feel.
- Other projects I developed and maintained included Playboy UK TV's other channels supporting sites such as the AdultChannel.co.uk, Climax3.co.uk, Prowler.tv, SpiceExtreme.co.uk, Bamboomag.co.uk, PlayboyModel.co.uk and PlayboyU.co.uk and helped on the Private Spice VOD.

5 recommendations available upon request

Web Designer at Harrods

July 2006 - October 2006 (4 months)

- Mainly keeping Harrods.com up to date with upcoming news, events and products.
- Working on brands such as Emporio Armani, Guerlain, La Prairie and many others.
- Creating design work such as landing pages and micro-sites.

• Developing them with the use of XHTML and CSS and the Harrods CMS.

Banner work using animated gifs for Harrods.com and its affiliated websites.

Freelance Junior Web Designer at DC Interact

April 2006 - June 2006 (3 months)

Website amendments to content and graphics for a number of clients including Tesco Personal Finance and Littlewoods.

Maintaining clients' website banners and XHTML and CSS coding for mock-ups and micro-sites.

DVD Designer (Authoring) at Wunderman

December 2005 - February 2006 (3 months)

- Putting together the DVD menu for the new 2006 'Jaguar XK' car release.
- Managing the layout of assets such as images and videos for optimum size and quality to output as a 16:9 professional widescreen DVD menu.
- Extensive testing with various TV screen resolutions to ensure compatibility at maximum quality.

Education

SAE Institute

2:1, Multimedia Arts, 2001 - 2004

International School of Geneva

International Baccalaureate, 1990 - 2000

Interests

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, iQuery

Skills & Expertise

Semantic HTML

HTML 5

CSS3

jQuery

W3C Standards

HTML emails

PSD to Wordpress

Cross-browser Compatibility

Adobe Creative Suite

Rohan Chambers

Social Media Technologist at We Are Social

rohanchambers888@yahoo.com



10 people have recommended Rohan

"I worked with Rohan on a number of projects during my time at Collective, and always found him to be knowledgeable, detail-oriented and confident developer. He was invaluable in helping diagnose issues, and often went outside his role to assist in deployments and testing."

— Greg Machray, Project Manager, Collective London, managed Rohan at Collective London

"Rohan ... What can I say about Rohan? Other than being a great developer, he's a wonderful person to work with. I've worked with him on a few projects, and as an Account Executive with very limited knowledge of coding - he was very good at explaining what we could and couldn't do for the clients. In situations where we couldn't, he always recommended clever build solutions to work around this. Alongside his experience, he's excellent at giving head massages and is one of the best people I've had the pleasure to work with."

— **Asmaa Sehli**, *Digital Account Executive*, *Collective London*, worked directly with Rohan at Collective London

"I worked with Rohan on a number of Social Media based projects, creating Facebook apps for a broad range of clients. Each app had unique mechanisms of entry, as well as advanced backend systems. Rohan has a great knowledge of what works and creates the best engagement from an interactive point of view. His skills were highly regarded both internally and with clients. I'd definitely be happy to work with him again."

— Tom Brickley, Community Manager, Collective London, worked with Rohan at Collective London

"When I arrived at Collective I found Rohan to be passionate about the code he produced but sometimes lacking confidence. In the year I spent working with him his confidence grew as did his knowledge and he became a valuable asset to the team. His passion for learning, especially in Javascript has really propelled him over the last year from owning small projects on his own to taking on large parts in a big site build where he was integral in the delivery of the Support your team project within the London 2012 Olympic site. Rohan is a nice guy to work with, has a good sense of humour and is pretty handy at Bomberman"

— Greg Sines, Technical Team Lead, Collective London, managed Rohan at Collective London

"Rohan designed and developed a company website for us. He was very detail orientated and has great web design skills. Rohan consulted with us every step of the way and we were very pleased with the outcome of the project."

- Andrew Ashley, was Rohan's client

"Rohan has a warm and friendly persona and makes everyone feel special from the moment they meet him. I am honoured to have had the pleasure of working with him and would not hesitate to work with him again. He truly is an asset in any organisation."

— Madhurika Gohil, BA (Hons), FCCA, Chief Accountant, Playboy TV UK/Benelux Ltd, worked directly with Rohan at Playboy Enterprises, Inc.

"I thoroughly enjoyed working with Rohan for a number years at Playboy UK and was impressed by Rohan's strong work ethic, attention to detail and his ability to keep work enjoyable. Rohan worked to tough time constraints in a high-pressure environment but always remained friendly and approachable. I'd thoroughly recommend Rohan for his slick devloping skills and great approach to tough challenges."

— **Oliver Spring**, *Marketing Manager*, *Playboy TV UK*, worked directly with Rohan at Playboy Enterprises, Inc.

"Rohan and I worked on the same team for a number of years. I always found him to be extremely helpful and knowledgeable. We shared ideas and returned creative solutions to deadline and budget. Personally my knowledge within the industry was aided greatly by working with Rohan and I wouldn't hesitate to recommend him for employment."

— **Karen Howard**, *Senior Production Co-ordinator / Project Manager*, *Playboy TV*, worked directly with Rohan at Playboy Enterprises, Inc.

"Rohan is a fun and skilled professional, with whom I worked with for a couple of years at Playboy UK. He's a very committed, easy going, team player who consistently produced a high level of quality development work. Rohan always worked hard to keep his build as close as possible to my final UI designs which I really admired. He went above and beyond to get projects done to the best of his ability, and is a great chap to have in any team. I highly recommend Rohan and hope that someday we're able to collaborate again."

— **Benjamin Anthonisz**, *Senior Designer*, *Playboy UK*, worked directly with Rohan at Playboy Enterprises, Inc.

"Working with Rohan at Playboy was a pleasure. He was able to take a brief first time and worked to some very tight deadlines, always delivering on-time, and his development work as I remember it was always accurate and to the brief given. Rohan also went the extra mile and on more than one occasion he thought outside the box and put in extra dev work to make the sites look and feel even better than what I had asked for. Rohan is professional, knows his stuff, and is also very friendly and approachable. He would be an asset to any employer and I would work with him again any day."

— **Anthony Fox**, *Online Marketing Executive*, *Playboy UK Ltd*, worked directly with Rohan at Playboy Enterprises, Inc.

Contact Rohan on LinkedIn